<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>erickuhn19.com</title>
  <subtitle>Blog</subtitle>
  <id>http://erickuhn19.com</id>
  <link href="http://erickuhn19.com"/>
  <link href="http://erickuhn19.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-07-04T20:53:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Photo Management Workflow</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://erickuhn19.com/photo-management-workflow/"/>
    <id>http://erickuhn19.com/photo-management-workflow/</id>
    <published>2016-07-04T20:53:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-04T21:18:28-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Fourth of July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always taken photos on my iPhone but ever since my son was born my wife and I have put more emphasis on using our DSLR. I bought the Canon Mark II 7D for my wife but recently I've gotten really interested in learning more about photography and using a high quality camera. I still have much to learn about how to use the camera, photography in general and doing some light editing, but the first thing I needed to tackle was how to manage the large influx of non-iPhone photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current set up is a MacBook Air with 128gb hard drive with an external 1tb drive used for backups through TimeMachine. The problem is that 128gb drive, it's almost filed up and I haven't even started adding hundreds of photos or the massive RAW files. I forgot to mention I pay for the 50gb of iCloud backup and all photos from my wife and my iPhone's are backed up to the Apple Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I tried was taking all the photos and importing them into my Photos app which then gets backed up to iCloud and is accessible on any of my devices. The problem is when shooting with the DSLR you take a ton of throw a way photos with the idea you will edit and delete many later. Adding them all to my iCloud which then get sorted by date with all my other iPhone photography was not ideal. Especially since my wife and I are both using the camera and now I have a full photo shoot she did with her sister on my photo library. That is not going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While looking for other options I remembered seeing a blog post by &lt;a href="https://www.caseyliss.com/2016/5/29/photo-management"&gt;Casey Liss&lt;/a&gt; about his photo management process, which got me thinking. I seriously considered using his script but know it would have taken me a while to customize it to fit my own needs. So I started to research options that I could get up and running quicker (I had a hundred new photos on the SD card waiting to be backed up after the iCloud debacle). &lt;a href="http://www.leancrew.com/all-this/2013/10/photo-management-via-the-finder/"&gt;The article Casey Liss was inspired by&lt;/a&gt; mentioned a Mac app called &lt;a href="https://www.noodlesoft.com/"&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;. I downloaded the trial and set up a rule to move all photos from the SD card once inserted into the Mac to be moved into the external hard drive and create a folder for each date a picture was taken. It works like magic and when I pop in the SD card all the photos are instantly moved into the external drive and sorted by date with the file name being a date and then numbered in ascending order. The SD card is wiped clean, ready to take more photos. Looking forward to learning more about the power of Hazel, this [Mac Power User Podcast episode])https://www.relay.fm/mpu/322) is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screen shot of my Hazel rule" class="responsive-img" src="/images/hazel_screenshot.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have all my DSLR photos on my external hard drive but not being backed up anywhere else. Side note, it would be ideal if the photos were to be put on my Mac's hard drive and then copied to the external but I'll have to wait to add that in to my workflow once I buy a new MacBook Pro with a tb+ of SSD. I've heard a lot of great things about &lt;a href="https://www.backblaze.com/"&gt;BackBlaze&lt;/a&gt; and have been meaning to have a second backup of all my data and this was perfect timing. I signed up for BackBlaze and fully prepared to pay past the trial. For $5 a month to know I have all my data backed up from my Mac and external drive is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step of my photo management process takes place once I've edited a photo and decided I really want to see it more often. I'll import into my Apple Photos app which will then be synced to iCloud and accessible on all my devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A minimum of two backups (external hard drive and BackBlaze) and a maximum of four backups (Mac, external, BackBlaze and iCloud).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will certainly evolve over time. Look forward to sharing when it does. I'll end with a photo of my amazing son Luca.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Luca on July 4th" class="responsive-img" src="/images/Luca_7_4_16.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>App Store Changes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://erickuhn19.com/app-store-changes/"/>
    <id>http://erickuhn19.com/app-store-changes/</id>
    <published>2016-06-13T20:44:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-13T21:21:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post comes a little late as I wrote it last week and the WWDC keynote was today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway! Ahead of WWDC, Phil Schiller broke news on changes to the app store with interviews to &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/6/8/11880730/apple-app-store-subscription-update-phil-schiller-interview"&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/2016/06/the_new_app_store"&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt;. This move was quite interesting and after hearing the keynote I see why. Those two hours went by so fast! I’m glad the developer community had time to digest what this means for their business. So many awesome updates for from the keynote…for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="app-review"&gt;App Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Apple is acknowledging that app review times have been drastically better over the last few weeks. I covered this an a earlier blog post and it’s great news that Apple is actually committing to doing this for the foreseeable future. This is hands down a win for developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="subscription-business-model"&gt;Subscription Business Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscription pricing is now open to all categories and after 12 months of paying for a subscription, the developer will now get 85% instead of 70%! It’s still a monumental task to have a user pay for 12+ months, but I’m glad to see Apple moving in this direction. Allowing developers to decide which business model fits for them is the right call, ultimately users will decide if they are willing to pay for a subscription if the app is continually providing value. and making the economics better.  regardless what type of app it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see how this changes the economic landscape for indie developers. From a users perspective, what will the UX of paying for individual apps on a rolling basis be? There will be breaking point on how many subscription apps a person is willing to pay for. However, I think only a small number of apps will adopt this model and it will therefore have a net positive effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ads-in-search"&gt;Ads in Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple seems to be adamant that Ads in Search will not become like other ad exchanges and will be tightly controlled so the tool won’t be abused. I tend to agree it will be done in a tasteful manner. Looking past the potential downfalls, this is a great opportunity for a new app to break into a category where they wouldn’t be close to the top of search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing if these changes help the app store economics for indie developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Building a chat app with Firebase and Swift</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://erickuhn19.com/building-a-chat-app-with-firebase-and-swift/"/>
    <id>http://erickuhn19.com/building-a-chat-app-with-firebase-and-swift/</id>
    <published>2016-05-30T22:54:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-05-30T22:55:49-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So in my &lt;a href="http://erickuhn19.com/google-io-2016-thoughts/"&gt;last post on Google I/O&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned I was going to explore Firebase and I’ve been doing just that. The Firebase team has great documentation on their site as well as some helpful tutorials. I completed the iOS building a messaging app with Swift. You can find the link &lt;a href="https://codelabs.developers.google.com/codelabs/firebase-ios-swift"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very cool to see the power behind the SDK and how Firebase can augment so many backend things you would have to build into your API. I followed along but getting to understand all the functions is really where you can unlock Firebase’s true potential. I plan on doing this over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the tutorial you learn how to set up the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sync data using the Firebase Realtime Database.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage Identity and Sign In with Firebase Authentication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store and access files using Firebase Storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure an application with Firebase Remote Config.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Track application usage flows with Firebase Analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Display ads with AdMob.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there were a few issues with the documentation. Nothing a little stackoverflow/github googling couldn’t fix. Here are the fixes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Section 8: &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/37383187/error-in-firebase-ios-codelab-chat-app-tutorial"&gt;stackoverflow link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to add to the Constants.Swift file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;swift
static let imageUrl = "imageUrl"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All looked good after that and then I caught this error when I complied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;FriendlyChatSwift[7097:353609] &lt;em&gt;** Assertion failure in -[UITableView _endCellAnimationsWithContext:], /BuildRoot/Library/Caches/com.apple.xbs/Sources/UIKit_Sim/UIKit-3512.60.7/UITableView.m:1716 2016-05-28 16:38:42.950 FriendlyChatSwift[7097:353609] **&lt;/em&gt; Terminating app due to uncaught exception 'NSInternalInconsistencyException', reason: 'Invalid update: invalid number of rows in section 0.  The number of rows contained in an existing section after the update (1) must be equal to the number of rows contained in that section before the update (27), plus or minus the number of rows inserted or deleted from that section (1 inserted, 0 deleted) and plus or minus the number of rows moved into or out of that section (0 moved in, 0 moved out).'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the discussion on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/firebase/friendlychat/issues/25"&gt;Firebase’s github page&lt;/a&gt; on the issue. The answer that ended up working for me came from this source on &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/37400316/image-upload-crash-in-firebase-codelabs-friendlychat-tutorial"&gt;stackoverflow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found an error in step 10, use this in the viewDidLoad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;swift
self.remoteConfig = FIRRemoteConfig.remoteConfig()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Google I/O 2016 thoughts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://erickuhn19.com/google-io-2016-thoughts/"/>
    <id>http://erickuhn19.com/google-io-2016-thoughts/</id>
    <published>2016-05-22T22:03:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-05-22T22:04:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Google IO 2016" src="/images/googleio2016.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t going to be a full write up of Google I/O 2016. There are many that do a great job of that, you can read &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/gallery/everything-you-need-to-know-from-the-2016-google-io-keynote/"&gt;TechCrunch’s here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/5/18/11701030/google-io-2016-keynote-highlights-announcements-recap"&gt;The Verge here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2016/05/20/google-io-2016-recap-everything-need-know/#gref"&gt;The Next Web here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to touch on the two things that I am really excited about. The first is Google Home. I’ve been excited about Amazon’s Echo but haven’t jumped in yet. I’ve read and seen examples where the Echo can be a really cool utility because of it’s always listening functionality. I air on the side of Siracusa here &lt;a href="http://atp.fm/episodes/170"&gt;(listen to the ATP 170 to hear his thoughts)&lt;/a&gt; and think that the the full stack integrations with merchants isn’t there yet, so it won’t be able to do the things I really would like it to do. However, if I trust any company to do this really well, it’s Google. Google’s core competency is in big data processing and machine learning which is exactly what this product is meant for. I will 100% be a buyer of this product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only my new Apple TV had the always listening functionality with enhanced microphones. Apple could have already had a horse in this race. Siri on iPhone and Apple Watch isn’t sufficient because the ‘hey siri’ is way too hit or miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://marco.org/2016/05/21/avoiding-blackberrys-fate"&gt;Marco Arment writes up a great piece&lt;/a&gt; on his fear that Apple is not focusing enough on the machine learning/AI strategy, where its competitors already have an advantage. Let’s see if Apple opens up a Siri API at WWDC next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other Google IO announcement that is really exciting and I plan on diving in much deeper with, is &lt;a href="https://firebase.google.com/"&gt;Firebase.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Firebase" src="/images/firebase.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firebase was purchased around 18 months ago and this is the &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/5/18/11704050/google-firebase-baas-facebook-parse-google-io-2016"&gt;first major addition to the platform.&lt;/a&gt; With &lt;a href="http://blog.parse.com/announcements/moving-on/"&gt;Parse shutting down&lt;/a&gt; this is a welcome to the developer community that want to rely on back end as a service (BaaS) platforms. I am personally excited and already diving into the documentation to see how I could utilize this service in my next side project. The reason why it’s so intriguing? Google is building this platform to be multi channel: iOS, Android and Web. Back end services are one of those things Google does well and this update to Firebase is going to help fill the void where Parse left off.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Solving customer problems in payments</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://erickuhn19.com/solving-customer-problems-in-payments/"/>
    <id>http://erickuhn19.com/solving-customer-problems-in-payments/</id>
    <published>2016-05-17T21:28:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-05-17T22:03:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting announcement was made this week in the payments world. MCX is laying off 30 people and postponing their launch of the CurrentC mobile payment app. You can read about the announcement on &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2016/05/16/mcx-postpones-national-rollout-of-apple-pay-rival-currentc-lays-off-30-to-focus-on-banks"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/2016/05/translation_mcx"&gt;John Gruber, on his site Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; does a comical, yet glaringly true translation of the comments made by the CEO of MCX. And &lt;a href="http://www.pymnts.com/news/mobile-payments/2016/mcx-currentc-mobile-wallet-postponed/"&gt;PYMNTS.com&lt;/a&gt; has a write up about the story that brings up pressing questions to be answered in the mobile payments space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we’ve learned anything over the last several years when watching the mobile payments field take shape, it’s that absent something that solves a problem for a consumer or adds value to their experience, innovators have nothing left but an empty bank account to show for their efforts. And the longer that it takes for the value exchange to be recognized and that “ignition” to happen, the more likely it is that a superior offer comes along to take its place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This point is essential. The plastic cards have been solving the problems of consumers for years. The next wave of solutions needs to solve a new problem and really add value to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking about an &lt;a href="https://stratechery.com/2015/chase-pay-and-the-payments-stack-apple-pay-and-opportunity-cost-apply-aggregation-theory/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; I read late last year echoing the same sentiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll jump straight to the punchline: Chase Pay will fail. Understanding why, though, is interesting, and the fact this exists at all should be worrying from an Apple perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;First off, like most products produced by companies which don’t owe their existence or financial performance to the quality of the user experience, the product already sounds like a complete mess: you pay with QR codes from the Chase app, except for when you need QR codes from the MCX app, and hey, you can sometimes take a photo of your check and not use QR codes as well! It’s ridiculous, and as I’ve said about payments from the beginning, whatever product succeeds credit cards has to be significantly easier to use; inertia is a powerful thing, which means the delta of improvement in convenience in particular (plus security and usefulness and all the other factors that you can attribute to a product) has to be massive. And, given just how convenient credit cards are, a new payment solution has to basically have zero friction — and this Chase product sounds like it has a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think these are all the right conversations to be having. Solving the needs of consumers has to be the focus in mobile payments and will be the catalyst to drive adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple shortens app review times</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://erickuhn19.com/apple-shortens-app-review-times/"/>
    <id>http://erickuhn19.com/apple-shortens-app-review-times/</id>
    <published>2016-05-14T13:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-05-14T13:05:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Kuhn</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There was been much talk about Apple competing and generating revenue as a service based business. If you haven't read the &lt;a href="https://stratechery.com/2016/apples-organizational-crossroads/"&gt;Stratechery blog post&lt;/a&gt; on it, it's a must read. Now there are reports that Apple is significantly cutting app review times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-05-12/apple-shortens-app-review-times-in-push-to-boost-service-sales"&gt;From Bloomberg :&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Apple Inc. has cut the approval time for new submissions to its App Store from more than a week to less than two days, part of a broader push to increase revenue from services including mobile applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a long awaited step in the right direction, however Apple still needs to focus on improving discoverability in the app store. Perhaps a purge of the massive volume of terrible apps in the store, especially the ones that haven't been updated in years. Quality &amp;gt; Quantity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen to Marco and Underscore talk about it on &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/+Fgm1ElCi0"&gt;Under the Radar: 27: Fast App Review.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
